Guide to the Witness to Guantanamo Video Collection, 2009-2017 RL.11691
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Interviews, 2009-2017; 10,000 Gigabytes secure server
  - Mohamed, Ben Moujane, 2012-07-11; 1:31:11
    - Mohamed, Ben Moujane - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BenMoujaneMohamed.mov)
  - Mora, Alberto, 2010-12-04; 2:35:11
    Alberto Mora, male, age 58, was the General Counsel of the Navy in 2001 and led efforts in the Department of Defense to oppose Bush administration legal theories that allowed harsh interrogation tactics at the U.S. detention camp in Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
    - Mora, Alberto - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AlbertoMora.mov)
    - Mora, Alberto - short clip - AmericanLeadershipOnHumanRights (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlbertoMora_AmericanLeadershipOnHumanRights.mp4)
  - Muhammed, Ayub, 2009-08-05; 2:26:42
    Ayub Muhammed, male, age 25, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from May 2002 until May 5, 2006, when he was released to Albania.
    - Muhammed, Ayub - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AyubMuhammed.mov)
    - Muhammed, Ayub - short clip - cage (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Ayub_cage.mp4)
    - Muhammed, Ayub - short clip - spoon (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Ayub_spoon_short.mp4)
    - Muhammed, Ayub - short clip - spoon (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AyubMuhammed_spoon.mp4)
    - Muhammed, Ayub - short clip - spoon2 (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AyubMuhammed_spoon2.mp4)
    - Muhammed, Ayub - short clip - USGov (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Ayub_USGov.mp4)
  - Mustafa, Khaled Ben, 2010-09-25; 2:43:26
    Khaled Ben Mustafa, male, age 38, French, was detained at Guantanamo February 13, 2002 until March 7, 2005, when he was returned to France for trial. Originally convicted in France in 2007, his trial was overturned on appeal and he was released in February 2009. Despite having already served the one-year sentence they faced, the Court of Cassation ordered a re-trial on February 17, 2010.
    - Mustafa, Khaled Ben - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KhaledBenMustafa.mov)
    - Mustafa, Khaled Ben - short clip - ADayintheLife (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhaledBenMustafa_ADayintheLife.mp4)
    - Mustafa, Khaled Ben - short clip - AllPartoftheSystem (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhaledBenMustafa_AllPartoftheSystem.mp4)
    - Mustafa, Khaled Ben - short clip - AllPartoftheSystem-old (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhaledBenMustafa_AllPartoftheSystem-old.mp4)
    - Mustafa, Khaled Ben - short clip - DetaineesProtestingandMilitaryResponse (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhaledBenMustafa_DetaineesProtestingandMilitaryResponse.mp4)
  - Nakhleh, Emile, 2013-04-10; 1:30:28
    Emile Nakhleh, male, age 74, was a senior intelligence service officer and director of the Political Islam Strategic Analysis Program in the Directorate of Intelligence at the CIA.
    - Nakhleh, Emile - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file EmileNakhleh.mov)
    - Nakhleh, Emile - short clip - HowTheyBecameJihadist (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file EmileNakhleh_HowTheyBecameJihadist.mp4)
    - Nakhleh, Emile - short clip - RecognizingRadicalMuslims (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file EmileNakhleh_RecognizingRadicalMuslims.mp4)
    - Nakhleh, Emile - short clip - TheGuantanamoGeneration (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file EmileNakhleh_TheGuantanamoGeneration.mp4)
  - Neely, Brandon, 2010-09-11; 1:28:58
    Brandon Neely, male, age 30, was stationed as a guard in Guantanamo from January 2002 until March 2004. In January 2010, he flew to the United Kingdom to meet with former detainees with whom he had reconnected via Facebook.
    - Neely, Brandon - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BrandonNeely.mov)
    - Neely, Brandon - short clip - ArrivalofFirstPrisoners (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrandonNeely_ArrivalofFirstPrisoners.mp4)
    - Neely, Brandon - short clip - DoittheRightWay (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrandonNeely_DoittheRightWay.mp4)
    - Neely, Brandon - short clip - Facebook (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BrandonNeely_Facebook.mp4)
  - Nelson, Torin, 2014-06-05; 2:01:39
    Torin Nelson, male, age 45, was an interrogator in Guantanamo Bay and Afghanistan, and has spoken out against the interrogation practices at Abu Ghraib.
    - Nelson, Torin - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file TorinNelson.mov)
    - Nelson, Torin - short clip - InexperiencedInterrogators (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TorinNelson_InexperiencedInterrogators.mp4)
    - Nelson, Torin - short clip - NoVoice (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TorinNelson_NoVoice.mp4)
    - Nelson, Torin - short clip - SlippingintotheGrayArea (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file TorinNelson_SlippingintotheGrayArea.mp4)
  - Newton, Michael, 2015-08-14; 2:28:27
    Michael Newton, male, age 53, served in the U.S. State Department's Office of War Crimes Issues from 1999-2002. As the senior advisor to the Ambassador-at-Large, Newton implemented a wide range of policy positions related to the law of armed conflict.
    - Newton, Michael - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MichaelNewton.mov)
  - Noori, Adel, 2010-01-04; 2:06:05
    Adel Noori., male, age 40, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from May 6, 2002 until October 31, 2009, when he was released to Palau. He won his habeas corpus suit in 2008, but was not released until the following year.
    - Noori, Adel - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AdelNoori.mov)
  - Nowak, Manfred, 2017-03-21; 1:58:25
    Manfred Nowak, male, age 66, is one of the leading human rights activists in the world. He was the United Nations Special Rapporteur on Torture from 2004-2010, and one of the five authors of a UN report on the detention of captives in Guantanamo.
    - Nowak, Manfred - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ManfredNowak.mov)
  - Odah, Khalid Al-, 2011-01-03; 0:50:38
    Khalid Al-Odah, male, age 58, is the father of detainee Fawzi Al-Odah, and the founder of the Kuwaiti Family Committee, an organization formed in 2004 by the relatives of detainees to advocate for their just treatment under the U.S. Judicial system. He campaigned for the release of 12 Kuwaiti detainees, the last of which, his son, was released from Guantanamo November 5, 2014, after almost 13 years of detainment without charge.
    - Odah, Khalid Al- - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file KhalidAl-Odah.mov)
    - Odah, Khalid Al- - short clip - GiveThemtheRight (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalidAl-Odah_GiveThemtheRight.mp4)
    - Odah, Khalid Al- - short clip - MissingOurSon (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalidAl-Odah_MissingOurSon.mp4)
    - Odah, Khalid Al- - short clip - OnBehalfofFawzi (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file KhalidAl-Odah_OnBehalfofFawzi.mp4)
  - Olshansky, Barbara, 2017-01-17; 2:27:33
    Barbara Olshansky, female, age 56, created and directed the advocacy project on behalf of Guantanamo detainees at the Center for Constitutional Rights, and is the author of "Secret Trials and Executions: Military Tribunals and the Threat to Democracy," and "Democracy Detained: Secret Unconstitutional Practices in the U.S. War on Terror."
    - Olshansky, Barbara - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BarbaraOlshansky.mov)
  - Padmanabhan, Vijay, 2012-04-14; 1:25:23
    Vijay Padmanabhan, male, age 34, worked in the U.S. State Department (2003-2008) as lead counsel on law of war litigation, collaborated with the Justice Department on Supreme Court cases, and led an inter-agency policy coordination committee on U.S. detention policy in the conflict with al Qaida.
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan.mov)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - DetaineeIdentificationProblems (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_DetaineeIdentificationProblems.mp4)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - DetaineeIdentificationProblems-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_DetaineeIdentificationProblems-review.mp4)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - GuantanamoAsACatalystForChange (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_GuantanamoAsACatalystForChange.mp4)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - GuantanamoAsACatalystForChange-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_GuantanamoAsACatalystForChange-review.mp4)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - MovingBeyondGuantanamosEarlyDays (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_MovingBeyondGuantanamosEarlyDays.mp4)
    - Padmanabhan, Vijay - short clip - MovingBeyondGuantanamosEarlyDays-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file VijayPadmanabhan_MovingBeyondGuantanamosEarlyDays-review.mp4)
  - Peirce, Gareth, 2013-06-15; 1:11:14
    Gareth Peirce, female, age 73, is a human rights attorney representing those accused of terrorist activity, including British citizens Moazzam Begg and Shakar Aamer.
    - Peirce, Gareth - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file GarethPeirce.mov)
    - Peirce, Gareth - short clip - BritishInvolvementinMoazzamBegg'sKidnappingandDetention (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GarethPeirce_BritishInvolvementinMoazzamBegg'sKidnappingandDetention.mp4)
    - Peirce, Gareth - short clip - SecretSitesRevealedbyAmericanBlunders (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GarethPeirce_SecretSitesRevealedbyAmericanBlunders.mp4)
    - Peirce, Gareth - short clip - UKHasNeverConfrontedAmerica (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file GarethPeirce_UKHasNeverConfrontedAmerica.mp4)
  - Pradhan, Alka, 2017-05-02; 2:20:30
    Alka Pradhan, female, age 35, is the Human Rights Counsel for the Guantanamo Bay Military Commission of the Department of Defense, and was also Counsel for The Constitution Project's Task-Force on Detainee Treatment, co-authoring a comprehensive report on U.S. detention practices since 2001.
    - Pradhan, Alka - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AlkaPradhan.mov)
    - Pradhan, Alka - short clip - 120DaysRestrained (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlkaPradhan_120DaysRestrained.mp4)
    - Pradhan, Alka - short clip - ClassificationofMemories (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlkaPradhan_ClassificationofMemories.mp4)
    - Pradhan, Alka - short clip - DoctorsoftheDarkSites (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AlkaPradhan_DoctorsoftheDarkSites.mp4)
  - Prosper, Pierre-Richard, 2015-03-04; 2:45:44
    Pierre-Richard Prosper, male, age 51, was the second United States Ambassador-at-Large for War Crimes Issues, the lead diplomat engaging with nations whose citizens were held in Guantanamo. He held the position under President George W. Bush from 2001 to 2005.
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper.mov)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - LackofCriticismofDrones (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_LackofCriticismofDrones.mp4)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - LackofCriticismofDrones-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_LackofCriticismofDrones-review.mp4)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - NoOneWantstoMaketheCall (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_NoOneWantstoMaketheCall.mp4)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - NoOneWantstoMaketheCall-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_NoOneWantstoMaketheCall-review.mp4)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - WhytheGenevaConventionsMayNotApply (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_WhytheGenevaConventionsMayNotApply.mp4)
    - Prosper, Pierre-Richard - short clip - WhytheGenevaConventionsMayNotApply-review (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Pierre-RichardProsper_WhytheGenevaConventionsMayNotApply-review.mp4)
  - Qasem, Abubakir, 2009-08-04; 2:15:45
    Abubakir Qasem, male, age 40, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from June 8, 2002 until May 5, 2006, when he was released to Albania.
    - Qasem, Abubakir - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AbubakirQasem.mov)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - ChineseDelegation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Abubakir_ChineseDelegation.mp4)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - ChineseDelegation (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbubakirQasem_ChineseDelegation.mp4)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - naked (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbubakirQasem_naked.mp4)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - nofuture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Abubakir_nofuture.mp4)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - nofuture (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbubakirQasem_nofuture.mp4)
    - Qasem, Abubakir - short clip - spy (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbubakirQasem_spy.mp4)
  - Rahman, Abdul Ghappar Abdul, 2010-01-03; 2:10:23
    Abdul Ghappar Abdul Rahman, male, age 36, a Uyghur from the Xinjiang autonomous region, was detained in Guantanamo from June 10, 2002 until October 31, 2009, when he was released to Palau.
    - Rahman, Abdul Ghappar Abdul - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file AbdulGhapparAbdulRahman.mov)
    - Rahman, Abdul Ghappar Abdul - short clip - english (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbdulGhabbar_english.mp4)
    - Rahman, Abdul Ghappar Abdul - short clip - goldenyears (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Abdul_goldenyears.mp4)
    - Rahman, Abdul Ghappar Abdul - short clip - learningenglish (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file AbdulGhabbar_learningenglish.mp4)
  - Rasul, Shafiq, 2009-08-16; 1:38:14
    Shafiq Rasul, male, age 32, British, was detained in Guantanamo from February 5, 2002 until March 9, 2004, when he was returned to Britain.
    - Rasul, Shafiq - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file ShafiqRasul.mov)
    - Rasul, Shafiq - short clip - English (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Shafiq_English.mp4)
    - Rasul, Shafiq - short clip - flighttoGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ShafiqRasul_flighttoGuantanamo.mp4)
    - Rasul, Shafiq - short clip - scaredguards (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file Shafiq_scaredguards.mp4)
    - Rasul, Shafiq - short clip - SpeakingEnglish (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file ShafiqRasul_SpeakingEnglish.mp4)
  - Ratner, Michael, 2010-04-16; 1:35:42
    Michael Ratner, male, age 66, is an attorney and the President of the Center for Constitutional Rights, and has represented Guantanamo detainees in front of the United States Supreme Court.
    - Ratner, Michael - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MichaelRatner.mov)
    - Ratner, Michael - short clip - CoupdEtat (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichaelRatner_CoupdEtat.mp4)
    - Ratner, Michael - short clip - DeprivedforOneDay (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MIchaelRatner_DeprivedforOneDay.mp4)
  - Rawi, Bisher al, 2011-08-02; 2:03:53
    Bisher al Rawi, male, age 43, an Iraqi citizen and resident of the UK, was detained in Guantanamo for four years (Feburary 2003- March 2007), and then released to Britain without charge.
    - Rawi, Bisher al - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file BisheralRawi.mov)
    - Rawi, Bisher al - short clip - GettingBacktoNormal (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BisheralRawi_GettingBacktoNormal.mp4)
    - Rawi, Bisher al - short clip - ThePainICarryInside (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BisheralRawi_ThePainICarryInside.mp4)
    - Rawi, Bisher al - short clip - UnnecessaryPunishment (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file BisheralRawi_UnnecessaryPunishment.mp4)
  - Reeck, Marc Van den, 2014-03-27; 1:33:26
    He crossed out mediation/arbitration clause in contract.
    Marc Van den Reeck, male, age unknown, is a Belgium Ambassador, and headed the Belgium delegation to Guantanamo to interview (and eventually resettle in Belgium) Syrian/Kurdish detainee Abdul Rahim Janko.
    - Reeck, Marc Van den - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MarcVandenReeck.mov)
    - Reeck, Marc Van den - short clip - NowYou'reDealingWithTheBelgians (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarcVandenReeck_NowYou'reDealingWithTheBelgians.mp4)
    - Reeck, Marc Van den - short clip - PreparingForJanko (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MarcVandenReeck_PreparingForJanko.mp4)
  - Remes, David, 2012-10-03; 3:07:13
    David Remes, male, age 57, gave up his career in corporate law to focus exclusively on representing Guantanamo Bay detainees. He represented Adnan Latif, a young Yemeni who died in September 2012 at Guantanamo Bay under suspicious circumstances.
    - Remes, David - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file DavidRemes.mov)
    - Remes, David - short clip - AnAdversarialRelationship (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DavidRemes_AnAdversarialRelationship.mp4)
    - Remes, David - short clip - DarkPrisoninKabul (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DavidRemes_DarkPrisoninKabul.mp4)
    - Remes, David - short clip - DarkPrisoninKabul (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file DavidRemes_DarkPrisoninKabul.mp4.mp4)
  - Rosenberg, Carol, 2011-11-14; 2:23:21
    Carol Rosenberg, female, age 52, a journalist for The Miami Herald, has covered the Guantanamo Bay detention center longer than any journalist, beginning with the arrival of the first prisoners on January 11, 2002.
    - Rosenberg, Carol - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file CarolRosenberg.mov)
    - Rosenberg, Carol - short clip - 10-YearEvolutionofDetention (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CarolRosenberg_10-YearEvolutionofDetention.mp4)
    - Rosenberg, Carol - short clip - ReportersUnderMilitaryEscort (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CarolRosenberg_ReportersUnderMilitaryEscort.mp4)
  - Rossdale, Polly, 2016-12-14; 1:30:55
    Polly Rossdale, female, age 38, was Deputy Director of Reprieve for two years, and for four years before that coordinated the Life after Guantanamo project, the only program dedicated to the rehabilitation of prisoners freed from Guantanamo.
    - Rossdale, Polly - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file PollyRossdale.mov)
    - Rossdale, Polly - short clip - LayersofChallenges (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PollyRossdale_LayersofChallenges.mp4)
    - Rossdale, Polly - short clip - MomentsofHope (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PollyRossdale_MomentsofHope.mp4)
    - Rossdale, Polly - short clip - RelationshipsDontAlwaysSurviveGuantanamo (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file PollyRossdale_RelationshipsDontAlwaysSurviveGuantanamo.mp4)
  - Salahi, Mahfoud Yahdih Ould, 2016-12-10; 1:52:40
    Mahfoud Yahdih Ould Salahi, male, age unknown, Mauritanian, discovered his brother, Mohamedou Ould Slahi, was being held in Guantanamo from a copy of Der Spiegel, a German weekly news magazine. He then worked tirelessly to raise awareness and get his brother released, which happened on Ocotber 17, 2016, after 14 years of detainment without charge.
    - Salahi, Mahfoud Yahdih Ould - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MahfoudYahdihOuldSalahi.mov)
  - Sassi, Nizar, 2017-03-19; 2:28:22
    Nizar Sassi, male, age 38, French of Tunisian descent, was detained in Guantanamo from February 15, 2002 until July 26, 2004, when he was returned to France. In 2012, Sassi and two other former French detainees filed a criminal complaint in Paris against the U.S. for use of torture in Guantanamo.
    - Sassi, Nizar - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file NizarSassi.mov)
  - Savage, Charlie, 2017-01-17; 1:07:03
    Charlie Savage, male, age 41, reports for The New York Times on national security and legal policy issues, including presidential power, surveillance, drone strikes, torture, secrecy, leak investigations, and Guantanamo Bay, Cuba.
    - Savage, Charlie - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file CharlieSavage.mov)
    - Savage, Charlie - short clip - ObamavsTrumpontheMilitaryCommissions (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CharlieSavage_ObamavsTrumpontheMilitaryCommissions.mp4)
    - Savage, Charlie - short clip - TheCripplingFearofAnExDetainee (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file CharlieSavage_TheCripplingFearofAnExDetainee.mp4)
  - Sawah, Tariq al-, 2016-07-02; 1:27:29
    Tariq al-Sawah, male, age 58, a citizen of Bosnia and Herzegovina and Egypt, was detained in Guantanamo from May 6, 2002 until January 20, 2016, when he was returned to Bosnia and Herzegovina. While in Guantanamo, he agreed to cooperate with the U.S. military, and became one of the most significant informants held at the prison. As a reward for his assistance, he was housed in a little fenced-in compound at the prison and provided a relatively easy life.
    - Sawah, Tariq al- - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file Tariqal-Sawah.mov)
  - Shamsi, Hina, 2017-03-10; 1:17:44
    Hina Shamsi, female, age 45, is Director of the ACLU National Security Project where she focuses on the intersection of national security and counterterrorism policies with international human rights and humanitarian law.
    - Shamsi, Hina - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file HinaShamsi.mov)
  - Shephard, Michelle, 2013-07-15; 1:20:58
    MichelleShephard, female, age 40, is an investigative reporter for the Toronto Star who has traveled to Guantanamo more than two dozen times to tell the stories of detainees, including Omar Khadr, one of the youngest Guantanamo prisoners and a Canadian citizen.
    - Shephard, Michelle - Interview master file (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0001, Video-file MichelleShephard.mov)
    - Shephard, Michelle - short clip - AnInternationalSymbol (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MIchelleShephard_AnInternationalSymbol.mp4)
    - Shephard, Michelle - short clip - AnInternationalSymbol-newwm (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MIchelleShephard_AnInternationalSymbol-newwm.mp4)
    - Shephard, Michelle - short clip - ArbitraryRules (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichelleShephard_ArbitraryRules.mp4)
    - Shephard, Michelle - short clip - TheDebateNeverChanges (Digital-materials RL11691-SET-0003, Video-file MichelleShephard_TheDebateNeverChanges.mp4)
  - Shimkus, Albert, 2011-08-09; 1:52:30
    Albert Shimkus, male, age 66, was the commanding officer and joint task force surgeon at the U.S. Naval Hospital in Guantanamo Bay, Cuba from January 2002 to July 2003.